Guide to the Robert Mearns Yerkes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional Correspondence, 1898-1982; Series I; 22.25 linear feet (54 boxes)
  - Bruhn, John M. (*), 1933-1945 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    See also: box 111, folders 2076-2078
  - Bryan, Alice I.
    See: box 69, folder 1322
  - Bryson, Lyman, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Buchholz, H.F.
    See: box 98, folders 1852-1853
  - Buck, J.L.
    See: box 57, folders 1086-1087
  - Burbridge, Benjamin (*), 1925-1936 (Box 8, Folder 125-126)
  - Burbridge, Juanita C. (Box 8, Folder 125-126)
  - Burleigh, Edith V.
  - Burnett, Charles T. (*), 1899-1946 (Box 8, Folder 127-128)
  - Burr, Harold S. (*), 1935-1948 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Burrow, Trigant (*), 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Burton, Marion L.
    See: box 70, folders 1346-1351
  - Burtt, Harold E., 1915-1945 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    See also: box 69, folder 1323 box 75, folder 1423
  - Buxton, Claude E., 1946-1956 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Buytendijk, F.J.J. (*), 1929-1952 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - "C" general, 1903-1954 (Box 8, Folder 134-137)
  - Calkins, Mary W. (*), 1900-1927 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Calmette, A.
    See: box 69, folders 1314-1316
  - Canby, Henry S. (*), 1932-1951 (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Cannon, Bernice, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Cannon, Cornelia J. (*), 1945-1969 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Cannon, Ida (*), 1910-1959 (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Cannon, Walter B. (*), 1903-1946 (Box 9, Folder 143-150)
    See also: box 70, folders 1338-1339
  - Cannon, Wilma, 1925, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - Carmichael, Leonard (*), 1927-1952 (Box 9, Folder 152-156)
    See also: box 72, folders 1380-1382 box 74, folders 1408-1409 box 99, folders 1869-1870
  - Carmichael, Leonard, 1954-1973 (Box 10, Folder 157-159)
  - Carpenter, Clarence Ray (*), 1930-1975 (Box 10, Folder 160-168)
    See also: box 66, folder 1248 box 111, folders 2076-2078
  - Carr, Harvey A. (*), 1912-1917 (Box 10, Folder 169)
  - Carrell, Alexis (*), 1926-1937 (Box 10, Folder 170)
  - Carson, John F., 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 171)
  - Carter, Morris
    See: box 155, folders 2433-2434
  - Castle, William E. (*), 1908-1925 (Box 10, Folder 172)
  - Cattel, J. McKeen (*), 1900-1944 (Box 10, Folder 173-174)
    See also: box 72, folders 1372-1373 box 83, folders 1615-1619
  - Chalmers, C.H., 1943 (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - Chapman, Elizabeth (*), 1915-1919 (Box 11, Folder 176)
  - Chapman, Frank M. (*), 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 177)
    See also: box 63, folders 1189-1190
  - Chapman, William H., 1912-1925 (Box 11, Folder 178)
  - Chisholm, Brock, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 179)
  - Claparède, Edouard
    See: box 61, folders 1158-1160
  - Clark, Hubert L. (*), 1912-1941 (Box 11, Folder 180)
  - Cleland, Ralph E.
    See: box 80, folders 1528-1530
  - Cobb, Margaret, 1920-1955 (Box 11, Folder 181)
  - Cobb, Stanley, 1932-1934 (Box 11, Folder 182)
  - Coblentz, William W., 1913 (Box 11, Folder 183)
  - Coburn, Charles A. (*), 1911-1956 (Box 11, Folder 184)
  - Coghill, George E. (*), 1938-1941 (Box 11, Folder 185)
  - Cole, Lawrence W. (*), 1905-1937 (Box 11, Folder 186-189)
  - Cole, Leon J. (*), 1907-1947 (Box 11, Folder 190)
  - Colwell, Howard S., 1937-1955 (Box 11, Folder 191)
  - Conant, James B (*), 1941-1953 (Box 11, Folder 192)
    See also: box 68, folders 1301-1303 box 68, folder 1306
  - Congdon, E.D., 1908-1922 (Box 11, Folder 193)
  - Conklin, Edwin G. (*), 1914-1954 (Box 11, Folder 194)
    See also: box 55, folders 1055-1056 box 106, folder 1998
  - Cook, Robert C., 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 195)
  - Coolidge, Harold J., Jr. (*), 1928-1929 (Box 11, Folder 196)
    See also: box 83, folder 1597
  - Coolidge, Harold J., Jr., 1930-1957 (Box 12, Folder 197-200)
  - Corey, Hilda Irene (Mrs. William F. Diller) (*), 1924-1956 (Box 12, Folder 201)
  - Corner, George W. (*), 1919-1963 (Box 12, Folder 202-204)
    See also: box 72, folder 1386 box 77, folders 1459-1463
  - Counts, George S. (*), 1931-1947 (Box 12, Folder 205)
  - Cowdry, Edmond V. (*), 1931-1963 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    See also: box 98, folder 1843
  - Cowles, John T. (*), 1934-1963 (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - Craig, Wallace (*), 1907-1944 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Crawford, Meredith P. (*), 1934-1940 (Box 12, Folder 209-211)
  - Crawford, Meredith P., 1941-1978 (Box 13, Folder 212)
  - Crook, Guy Hamilton (*), 1936-1939 (Box 13, Folder 213)
  - Culler, Elmer A. (*), 1937-1944 (Box 13, Folder 214)
  - Cummings, Bruce F., 1909-1911 (Box 13, Folder 215)
  - Cunningham, Alyse (*), 1924-1931 (Box 13, Folder 216)
  - Cushing, Harvey (*), 1908-1947 (Box 13, Folder 217-220)
  - "D" general, 1899-1955 (Box 13, Folder 221-223)
  - Dallenbach, Karl M., 1928-1951 (Box 13, Folder 224)
    See also: box 74, folders 1404-1406
  - Dana, Edward S. (*), 1925-1934 (Box 13, Folder 225)
  - Darby, Hamilton, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 226)
  - Darby, James C. (*), 1930-1951 (Box 13, Folder 227-228)
  - Dashiel, John F., 1937-1947 (Box 13, Folder 229)
  - Davenport, Charles B. (*), 1899-1942 (Box 13, Folder 230)
    See also: box 60, folder 1145 box 80, folders 1534-1536
  - Davidson, Eugene A., 1947-1955 (Box 13, Folder 231)
  - Davis, Jerome (*), 1925-1934 (Box 13, Folder 232)
  - Davis, Katharine B. (*), 1926-1935 (Box 14, Folder 233)
  - Davis, Watson, 1952-1954 (Box 14, Folder 234)
    See also: box 82, folders 1596-1598
  - Davis, William H. (*), 1899-1905 (Box 14, Folder 235)
  - Davis, William M. (*), 1912-1931 (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - Day, Edmund E. (*), 1928-1945 (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - Dean, Brashford, 1923-1925 (Box 14, Folder 238)
  - Dearborn, Walter F. (*), 1912-1953 (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - Delorme, Maurice
    See: box 69, folders 1315-1316
  - Deming, Clyde L. (*), 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - Denis, Armand (*), 1934-1946 (Box 14, Folder 241)
    See also: box 66, folder 1251 box 72, folder 1386
  - Dennis, Wayne (*), 1941-1955 (Box 14, Folder 242)
  - Derscheid, Jean M. (*), 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 243)
  - Dethier, Vincent G., 1940-1950 (Box 14, Folder 244)
  - Dewey, John, 1934-1952 (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Dice, Lee R. (*), 1936-1955 (Box 14, Folder 246)
  - Dickerson, Mary C. (*), 1907-1917 (Box 14, Folder 247)
  - Dittus, C.W.
    See: box 63, folders 1185-1186 box 98, folder 1846 box 100, folder 1881
  - Dodge, Heuri (Mrs. Raymond Dodge) (*), 1930-1954 (Box 14, Folder 248)
  - Dodge, Raymond (*), 1910-1978 (Box 14, Folder 249-251)
  - Dodge, Raymond: Biographical materials (*), 1942 (Box 14, Folder 252)
  - Dodson, J.D. (*), 1908-1932 (Box 14, Folder 253)
  - Doll, Edgar A. (*), 1917-1956 (Box 14, Folder 254-256)
  - Domarus, Eilhard von (*), 1928-1934 (Box 15, Folder 257)
  - Donaldson, Henry H. (*), 1907-1937 (Box 15, Folder 258)
  - Dorcus, Roy M.
    See: box 62, folders 1179-1183 box 63, folders 1186-1187
  - Downey, June E., 1918-1932 (Box 15, Folder 259)
  - Drew, Gilman A., 1930-1934 (Box 15, Folder 260)
  - Dunlap, Knight (*), 1929-1940 (Box 15, Folder 261)
    See also: box 62, folders 1173-1181 box 63, folders 1185-1186
  - Dusser de Barenne, J.G. (*), 1929-1940 (Box 15, Folder 262)
  - "E" general, 1915-1955 (Box 15, Folder 263)
  - Eames, Burton E. (*), 1906-1949 (Box 15, Folder 264-269)
  - Eames, F. LeRoy (*), 1925-1950 (Box 15, Folder 270)
  - Eastman, Max (*), 1932-1936 (Box 15, Folder 271)
  - Eaton, Paul (*), 1931-1938 (Box 15, Folder 272)
  - Eckstein, Gustav (*), 1927-1950 (Box 15, Folder 273-274)
  - Edgarton, Franklin, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 275)
  - Edinger, Ludwig, 1908-1951 (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - Edinger, Tilly (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - Eisenhart, Luther P., 1949-1955 (Box 16, Folder 277)
    See also: box 55, folders 1057-1059
  - Elder, James H. (*), 1929-1949 (Box 16, Folder 278-289)
    See also: box 66, folder 1253 box 111, folders 2076-2078
  - Eliot, Charles W. (*), 1904-1925 (Box 17, Folder 290)
  - Elliot, Richard M. (*), 1914-1976 (Box 17, Folder 291-298)
    See also: box 70, folder 1349
  - Ellis, Albert (*), 1949-1954 (Box 17, Folder 299)
  - Ellson, D.G., 1951 (Box 17, Folder 300)
  - Embree, Edwin R. (*), 1921-1949 (Box 17, Folder 301-302)
  - English, Horace B., 1943-1954 (Box 17, Folder 303)
  - Erikson, G.E., 1951-1952 (Box 17, Folder 304)
  - Evans, Herbert M. (*), 1933-1944 (Box 17, Folder 305)
  - Eyre, Louisa (*), 1926-1944 (Box 17, Folder 306-307)
  - Eyre, Louisa, 1945-1953 (Box 18, Folder 308-309)
  - "F" general, 1901-1957 (Box 18, Folder 310-311)
  - Fairchild, David (*), 1924-1954 (Box 18, Folder 312)
  - Fairchild, Henry P. (*), 1925-1956 (Box 18, Folder 313)
    See also: box 82, folders 1568-1570
  - Farabee, William Cortis, 1917-1926 (Box 18, Folder 314)
  - Farris, Edmond J., 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 315)
  - Felce, Winifred H. (*), 1940-1950 (Box 18, Folder 316)
  - Felix, Robert H., 1955 (Box 18, Folder 317)
  - Fels, Samuel S. (*), 1942-1950 (Box 18, Folder 318-319)
  - Fernberger, Samuel W., 1939-1951 (Box 18, Folder 320)
  - Fernald, Mabel R. (*), 1916-1921 (Box 18, Folder 321)
  - Fernald, Walter E. (*), 1911-1920 (Box 18, Folder 322)
  - Fields, Paul E., 1933-1936 (Box 18, Folder 323)
  - Finch, Glen (*), 1936-1954 (Box 18, Folder 324-326)
  - Fischel, Werner (*), 1932-1950 (Box 18, Folder 327)
  - Fisher, Vardis, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 328)
  - Fitzgerald, Alice (*), 1929-1941 (Box 18, Folder 329)
  - Fletcher, F. Milford (*), 1935-1955 (Box 18, Folder 330)
  - Flexner, Abraham (*), 1907-1959 (Box 19, Folder 331-335)
  - Flexner, Simon (*), 1909-1943 (Box 19, Folder 336)
    See also: box 57, folder 1095
  - Flinn, Alfred D. (*), 1921-1935 (Box 19, Folder 337-339)
  - Foley, John P., Jr. (*), 1934 (Box 19, Folder 340)
  - Foot, Katherine, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 341)
  - Ford, Guy Stanton, 1925-1957 (Box 19, Folder 342)
  - Forster, Milton C. (*), 1932-1938, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 343)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1925-1930 (Box 19, Folder 344)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. (*), 1923-1949 (Box 19, Folder 345)
  - Foster, William S. (*), 1915-1931 (Box 19, Folder 346)
  - Foster, Josephine Curtis (*), 1915-1931
    See also: box 98, folder 1858
  - Fox, Herbert
    See: box 113, folders 2128-2130
  - Franck, James, 1951-1955 (Box 19, Folder 347)
  - Frandsen, Peter (*), 1898-1946 (Box 19, Folder 348)
  - Frandsen, Peter, 1947-1956 (Box 20, Folder 349)
  - Frank, Glen, 1925-1932 (Box 20, Folder 350)
  - Frank, Glen, Jr., 1925-1932 (Box 20, Folder 350)
  - Frank, Lawrence K. (*), 1926-1941 (Box 20, Folder 351)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1930-1942 (Box 20, Folder 352)
  - Franz, Shepherd I. (*), 1903-1929 (Box 20, Folder 353)
  - Freeman, Frank N. (*), 1922-1924 (Box 20, Folder 354)
  - Freethought, Press Association, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 355)
  - Frisch, Karl von (*), 1945-1954 (Box 20, Folder 356)
  - Fulchner, Gordon S., 1938 (Box 20, Folder 357)
  - Fulton, John F. (*), 1929-1956 (Box 20, Folder 358-363)
    See also: box 66, folder 1254 box 101, folders 1907-1908 box 112, folder 2109
  - "G" general, 1912-1955 (Box 20, Folder 364-367)
  - Galt, William E., 1939-1946 (Box 21, Folder 368)
  - Gamble, Eleanor A. McC. (*), 1914-1917 (Box 21, Folder 369)
  - Gantt, W. Horsley (*), 1929-1946 (Box 21, Folder 370)
  - Gavan, James A. (*), 1951-1954 (Box 21, Folder 371)
  - Gay, Frederick P. (*), 1934-1940 (Box 21, Folder 372)
  - Gellerman, Louis W. (*), 1929-1947 (Box 21, Folder 373-374)
  - Gengerelli, Joseph A. (*), 1928-1932 (Box 21, Folder 375)
  - Gesell, Arnold (*), 1924-1957 (Box 21, Folder 376)
  - Getz, George F.
    See: box 58, folder 1111
  - Gill, Rose Christine, 1915-1963 (Box 21, Folder 377)
  - Gillman, Joseph (*), 1938-1940 (Box 21, Folder 378)
  - Ginsberg, Eli, 1951-1953 (Box 21, Folder 379)
  - Given, Philip L. (*), 1944 (Box 21, Folder 380)
  - Glenn, John M. (*), 1925-1945 (Box 21, Folder 381)
  - Goddard, Henry H. (*), 1912-1918 (Box 21, Folder 382)
  - Goodenough, Florence L., 1936-1949 (Box 21, Folder 383)
  - Gould, Charles W. (*), 1924-1933 (Box 21, Folder 384-388)
    See also: box 1, folder Accession 1989-M-076
  - Gould, Charles W., estate of (*), 1931-1936 (Box 22, Folder 389)
  - Gould, Charles W., proposed memorial to (*), 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 390)
  - Graham, Clarence H. (*), 1946-1955 (Box 22, Folder 391)
  - Grant, Madison, 1925-1937 (Box 22, Folder 392)
  - Gray, George W.
    See: box 77, folders 1459-1460
  - Greene, Jerome D. (*), 1915-1936 (Box 22, Folder 393)
  - Greene, Joseph I. (*), 1942-1948 (Box 22, Folder 394)
  - Greenfield, B. Spencer (*), 1909-1914 (Box 22, Folder 395-396)
  - Greenman, Milton J. (*), 1907-1937 (Box 22, Folder 397-398)
    See also: box 106, folders 1999-2001
  - Greenway, James C.
    See: box 60, folders 1138-1139
  - Gregg, Alan (*), 1932-1956 (Box 22, Folder 399-401)
    See also: box 68, folders 1304-1305
  - Gregory, William K. (*), 1926-1950 (Box 22, Folder 402)
    See also: box 81, folder 1547 box 98, folder 1843
  - Grether, Walter, F. (*), 1937-1952 (Box 22, Folder 403-404)
  - Gruenberg, Frederick P.
    See: box 63, folders 1201-1204
    See: box 64, folder 1205
    See: box 64, folders 1206-1208
  - "H" general, 1898-1963 (Box 23, Folder 405-409)
  - Haan, J.A. Bierens de, 1949-1954 (Box 23, Folder 410)
  - Hadley, Philip B., 1909-1912 (Box 23, Folder 411)
  - Haggerty, M.E. (*), 1907-1955 (Box 23, Folder 412-414)
    See also: box 70, folders 1347-1348, 1351
  - Hagner, R. W.
    See: box 82, folder 1591
  - Haines, Thomas Harvey (*), 1901-1951 (Box 23, Folder 415)
  - Hale, George E. (*), 1916-1952 (Box 23, Folder 416-417)
  - Hale, William J., 1903-1955 (Box 23, Folder 418)
  - Hall, Arnold Bennett
    See: box 61, folders 1155-1157
  - Hall, G. Stanley (*), 1904-1926 (Box 23, Folder 419)
  - Hamilton, Gilbert Van Tassel (*), 1908-1914 (Box 23, Folder 420-421)
  - Hamilton, Gilbert Van Tassel, 1915-1973 (Box 24, Folder 422-426)
  - Hanford, A.C.
    See: box 162, folders 2533-2534
  - Hardwick, Rose S. (*), 1911-1917 (Box 24, Folder 427)
  - Harlow, Harry F. (*), 1934-1956 (Box 24, Folder 428)
    See also: box 67, folder 1258
  - Harrison, Ross (*), 1939-1943 (Box 24, Folder 429)
  - Harrison, Ross Granville (*), 1933-1948 (Box 24, Folder 430)
  - Harrison, Shelby M.
    See: box 69, folder 1319
  - Hartman, Carl (*), 1924-1968 (Box 24, Folder 431-434)
  - Harwell, Edalee Orcutt (*), 1959-1965 (Box 24, Folder 435)
    See also: box 67, folders 1259-1262
  - Haskins, Caryl (*), 1953-1955 (Box 24, Folder 436)
  - Haskins, Charles H., 1915-1921 (Box 24, Folder 437)
  - Haslerud, George M. (*), 1934-1943 (Box 24, Folder 438)
  - Haslerud, George M., 1945-1956, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 439-440)
  - Hasz, Marie E. (*), 1953-1955 (Box 25, Folder 441)
  - Hayes, Joseph W., 1922-1934 (Box 25, Folder 442)
  - Hayes, Mary H.S. (Box 25, Folder 442)
  - Hayes Keith J. (*), 1944-1960 (Box 25, Folder 443-446)
  - Hayes, Cathy (Box 25, Folder 443-446)
    See also: box 110, folders 2056-2058 box 110-111, folders 2059-2062
  - Hayes, Samuel P., Jr. (*), 1933, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 447)
  - Healy, William (*), 1911-1929 (Box 25, Folder 448-449)
  - Hebb, Donald O. (*), 1939-1955 (Box 25, Folder 450)
  - Helmle, Robert K., 1943-1945 (Box 25, Folder 451)
  - Hemplemann, Edith (*), 1938-1951 (Box 25, Folder 452)
  - Henmon, Katharine, 1926 (Box 25, Folder 453)
  - Henry, Susan R. (*), 1945-1950 (Box 25, Folder 454)
  - Herbert, Marvin J., 1942-1943 (Box 25, Folder 455)
  - Heron, W.T., 1927-1939 (Box 25, Folder 456)
  - Herrick. C. Judson (*), 1899-1943 (Box 25, Folder 457-460)
  - Herrick, C. Judson, 1944-1960 (Box 26, Folder 461-463)
  - Herrick, Francis H. (*), 1904-1912 (Box 26, Folder 464)
  - Herschberger, Ruth, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 465)
  - Highland, Scotland G. (*), 1945-1953 (Box 26, Folder 466)
  - Hilgard, Ernest R. (*), 1929-1956 (Box 26, Folder 467-468)
    See also: box 69, folders 1320-1321
  - Hill. W.C. Osman (*), 1950-1954 (Box 26, Folder 469)
  - Hirsch, Nathaniel M., 1926-1931 (Box 26, Folder 470)
  - Hocking, William E. (*), 1902-1958 (Box 26, Folder 471)
  - Hodgson, Casper, 1929-1931 (Box 26, Folder 472)
  - Hoernle, R.F. Alfred, 1916-1922 (Box 26, Folder 473)
  - Holmes, Henry W. (*), 1911-1939 (Box 26, Folder 474)
  - Holmes, S.J. (*), 1904-1916 (Box 26, Folder 475)
  - Holt, Edwin B. (*), 1901-1946 (Box 26, Folder 476)
  - Hooton, Earnest A. (*), 1916-1954 (Box 26, Folder 477)
  - Hornaday, William T.
    See: box 23, folder 412 box 113, folders 2120-2122
  - Horton, Charlotte E., 1949-1956 (Box 26, Folder 478)
  - Houser, J. David (*), 1924-1925 (Box 26, Folder 479)
  - Hovland, Carl I. (*), 1945-1966 (Box 26, Folder 480)
  - Howe, Harrison E. (*), 1921-1942 (Box 26, Folder 481)
  - Hoyt, E. Kenneth (*), 1933 (Box 26, Folder 482)
  - Hubbs, Carl L., 1942-1953 (Box 26, Folder 483)
  - Hull, Albert W. (*), 1945-1953 (Box 26, Folder 484)
  - Hull, Callie (*), 1925-1956 (Box 26, Folder 485)
  - Hull, Clark L. (*), 1929-1956 (Box 26, Folder 486-487)
  - Humphrey, George (*), 1949-1953 (Box 27, Folder 488)
  - Hunt, Edward E. (*), 1945-1953 (Box 27, Folder 489)
  - Hunter, Martha G.
    See: box 67, folders 1264-1265
  - Hunter, Walter S. (*), 1913-1956 (Box 27, Folder 490-491)
    See also: box 62, folders 1184-1187 box 71-72, folders 1371-1372 box 72, folder 1374
  - Huntington, Ellsworth (*), 1940-1946 (Box 27, Folder 492)
  - Hurme, Veikko O. (*), 1952-1954 (Box 27, Folder 493)
  - Husted, Ellery, 1933-1934 (Box 27, Folder 494)
  - Huxley, Julian (*), 1917-1936 (Box 27, Folder 495)
  - Hyde, Edward P.
    See: box 81, folders 1548-1549
  - "I" general, 1921-1954 (Box 27, Folder 496)
  - Ireland, Helen M. (*), 1925-1935 (Box 27, Folder 497)
  - "J" general, 1904-1955 (Box 27, Folder 498)
  - Jackson, Theodore A. (*), 1926-1942 (Box 27, Folder 499-500)
  - Jacobsen, Carlyle F. (*), 1930-1946 (Box 27, Folder 501-504)
  - James, William (*), 1902-1917 (Box 27, Folder 505)
  - Janson, H.W., 1953 (Box 27, Folder 506)
  - Jastrow, Joseph (*), 1899-1938 (Box 27, Folder 507)
  - Jaynes, Julian (*), 1965 (Box 27, Folder 508)
  - Jenkins, William O. (*), 1939-1951 (Box 27, Folder 509)
  - Jennings, Herbert S. (*), 1899-1922 (Box 27, Folder 510-511)
  - Jennings, Herbert S., 1922-1947 (Box 28, Folder 512)
  - Jessup, Walter A., 1942-1943 (Box 28, Folder 513)
  - Johnson, Frank, 1937-1939 (Box 28, Folder 514)
  - Johnson, Frederic B.
    See: box 103, folders 1932-1934
  - Johnson, H.M. (*), 1914-1929 (Box 28, Folder 515)
  - Johnson, Martin (*), 1929-1931 (Box 28, Folder 516)
  - Johnson, William B. (*), 1898-1941 (Box 28, Folder 517)
  - Johnston, Charles H. (*), 1907-1917 (Box 28, Folder 518)
  - Johnston, J.B.
    See: box 70, folder 1349
  - Johnstone, Edward R. (*), 1917-1943 (Box 28, Folder 519)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford (*), 1945-1955 (Box 28, Folder 520)
  - Joseph, Ellis S. (*), 1924-1931 (Box 28, Folder 521)
  - Judd, Charles H. (*), 1903-1921, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 522)
  - Judd, Helen M., 1913-1954 (Box 28, Folder 523)
  - "K" general, 1909-1963 (Box 28, Folder 524-525)
  - Kaempffert, Waldemar, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 526)
  - Kafka, Gustav, 1923-1929 (Box 28, Folder 527)
  - Kaplan, Sylvan, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 528)
  - Keeler, Clyde E. (*), 1925-1947 (Box 28, Folder 529)
  - Keith, Arthur (*), 1927-1951 (Box 28, Folder 530)
  - Kelemen, George (*), 1948-1950 (Box 28, Folder 531)
  - Keller, E.G., 1915 (Box 28, Folder 532)
  - Keller, Fred S., 1938-1949 (Box 28, Folder 533)
  - Kellogg, Vernon (*), 1921-1938 (Box 28, Folder 534)
  - Kellogg, Winthrop N. (*), 1930-1982 (Box 28, Folder 535-536)
  - Kelly, Arthur L.
    See: box 67, folder 1267
  - Kelly, Joan Morton
    See: box 67, folder 1268
  - Kempf, Edward J. (*), 1932-1942 (Box 28, Folder 537)
  - Kennard, Margaret A., 1945-1952 (Box 28, Folder 538)
  - Kennedy, John L. (*), 1936-1937 (Box 28, Folder 539)
  - Kerlin, Gilbert (*), 1931-1932 (Box 29, Folder 540)
  - Keyes, Kenneth, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 541)
  - Kinder, Elaine F. (*), 1944-1955 (Box 29, Folder 542)
  - Kinsey, Alfred C. (*), 1947-1956 (Box 29, Folder 543)
    See also: box 76, folders 1452-1460 box 80, folder 1530
  - Klauder, Charles Z.
    See: box 104, folders 1955-1956
  - Kleeck, Mary van (*), 1925-1948 (Box 29, Folder 544-545)
  - Kleinsasser, Alvin J. (*), 1940-1948 (Box 29, Folder 546)
  - Klüver, Heinrich (*), 1926-1955 (Box 29, Folder 547)
  - Koehler, Wolfgang (*), 1921-1953 (Box 29, Folder 548)
    See also: box 57, folder 1090
  - Kohts, Alexander E. (*), 1924-1966 (Box 29, Folder 549-552)
  - Kohts, Nadie (Kots, Nadezhda N. Ladygin) (*) (Box 29, Folder 549-552)
  - Kornhauser, Arthur, 1946-1949 (Box 29, Folder 553)
  - Krause, Gregor, 1926-1929 (Box 29, Folder 554)
  - Kuo, Zing Yang (*), 1922-1936 (Box 29, Folder 555)
  - "L" general (La-Le), 1899-1956 (Box 29, Folder 556)
  - "L" general (Li-Ly), 1902-1956 (Box 30, Folder 557-558)
  - La Barre, Weston, 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 559)
  - Ladd, Christine F., 1913, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 560)
  - Laird, Donald A. (*), 1921-1925 (Box 30, Folder 561)
  - Landis, Carney (*), 1924-1947 (Box 30, Folder 562)
  - Landon, John F. (*), 1942-1954 (Box 30, Folder 563)
  - Landsteiner, Karl, 1931 (Box 30, Folder 564)
  - Langfeld, Herhert S. (*), 1915-1958 (Box 30, Folder 565-568)
    See also: box 57, folders 1077-1083 box 76, folders 1450-1452
  - LaRue, Daniel W. (*), 1911-1969 (Box 30, Folder 569-571)
  - Lashley, Karl S. (*), 1915-1960 (Box 30, Folder 572)
    See also: box 70, folders 1346-1351 box 110, folders 2045-2058
  - Lasker, Gabriel, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 573)
  - Lasman, Paul, 1944-1948 (Box 30, Folder 574)
  - Lathrop, Abbie E.C. (*), 1906-1918 (Box 30, Folder 575-576)
  - Learned, Blanche (*), 1923-1932 (Box 31, Folder 577)
  - Learned, William S. (*), 1917-1950 (Box 31, Folder 578-581)
  - Lee, Richard C., 1952, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 582)
  - Lehman, Harvey C. (*), 1924-1953 (Box 31, Folder 583)
  - Leiter, Russell G., 1952-1953 (Box 31, Folder 584)
  - Leuba, Clarence (*), 1934-1952 (Box 31, Folder 585)
  - Levy, David M. (*), 1932-1955 (Box 31, Folder 586)
  - Lewis, Frederick T., 1915-1944 (Box 31, Folder 587)
  - Lewis, Margaret Child (*), 1925-1978 (Box 31, Folder 588-589)
    See also: box 99, folders 1869-1870
  - Ligon, Ernest M. (*), 1927-1948 (Box 31, Folder 590)
  - Lillie, Frank R. (*), 1905-1945, undated (Box 31, Folder 591-592)
    See also: box 106, folder 2002
  - Lillie, Ralph S., 1915-1952 (Box 31, Folder 593)
  - Lillie, Helen W. (*) (Box 31, Folder 593)
  - Lintz, Gertrude D. (*), 1932-1941 (Box 31, Folder 594)
  - Lippmann, Walter (*), 1922-1945 (Box 31, Folder 595)
  - Logan, John D. (*), 1898-1955 (Box 31, Folder 596)
  - Long, Cyril N.H., 1936-1956 (Box 31, Folder 597)
  - Long, Esmond R., 1937-1941 (Box 31, Folder 598)
  - Lorch, Emil, 1903-1904 (Box 31, Folder 599)
  - Lorenz, Konard, 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 600)
  - Loucks, Roger B. (*), 1933-1940 (Box 32, Folder 601)
  - Louttit, Chauncey M. (*), 1925-1956 (Box 32, Folder 602-603)
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence (*), 1910-1943 (Box 32, Folder 604)
  - Lutz, Frank E. (*), 1929-1933 (Box 32, Folder 605)
  - Lux, Geraldine, 1944-1947 (Box 32, Folder 606)
  - Lyon, E.P. (*), 1903-1936 (Box 32, Folder 607)
  - "M" general, 1899-1959 (Box 32, Folder 608-612)
  - McClung, Clarence E. (*), 1921-1946 (Box 32, Folder 613)
  - McCulloch, Thomas L. (*), 1932-1952 (Box 32, Folder 614-615)
  - McDougall, William (*), 1913-1938 (Box 32, Folder 616)
  - McGregor, James H. (*), 1926-1928 (Box 32, Folder 617)
  - McGregor, James H., 1929-1952 (Box 33, Folder 618)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1934-1951 (Box 33, Folder 619)
  - McNeal, Benjamin F. (*), 1940-1941 (Box 33, Folder 620)
  - McQuitty, Louis L., 1943-1945 (Box 33, Folder 621)
  - Malmo, Robert B. (*), 1936-1955 (Box 33, Folder 622)
  - Mansfield, George R. (*), 1924-1976 (Box 33, Folder 623)
  - Mansfield, Harvey C. (Box 33, Folder 623)
  - Mansfield, James S. (Box 33, Folder 623)
  - Mark, Edward L. (*), 1899-1946 (Box 33, Folder 624)
    See also: box 58, folder 1103